Luka Licheli

San Diego, CA 92105 (732) 586-4369 lukalicheli@gmail.com linkedin.com/in/lukalicheli lukalicheli.github.io/portfolio

I am a Full Stack Web Developer that is collaborative, but also a strong, independent, problem solver. Having used React paired with Material-UI Library, I have experience developing an intuitive user interface. I utilized reusable components and virtual DOM to give the app a mobile feel and used MongoDB and GraphQL to give it extensive functionality. With my time at Revature, I have also developed my back-end skills, using Java, Spring, AWS, and PostgreSQL paired with DBeaver, to build APIs that can function both locally and on the web. Currently, I am learning Angular to further solidify my front-end skills.

Experience

Revature 2022-Current (Expense Reimbursement System)

- Refactored an API that formerly used HTTP Servlets and Data Access Object pattern to a Spring application.
- Established a CD/CI Pipeline utilizing Amazon Web Services.
- Developed a polished UI using Angular, HTML, and CSS.
- Implemented user authentication and password encryption.
- Tools Used: Java, Spring, SQL, Angular, AWS, Postman

UCSD Extension Bootcamp *2021-2022* (Happy Hour)

- Implemented JWT Authentication to hash passwords before being saved to the database.
- Used GraphQL to implement business logic to the application.
- Utilized Apollo Server to create a connection from the back end to the front end.
- Developed a polished and intuitive UI using React, HTML, and CSS.
- Tools Used: Javascript, React, MongoDB, GraphQL, MongoDB Compass

Education

UC San Diego Extension 2021-2022 Certificate, Full Stack Web Development San Diego, CA

San Diego City College 2014-2021

San Diego, CA

Associates Degree, Business Administration

Technical Skills

- Javascript ES6+, Java 8/11
- React, Angular, jQuery, Bootstrap, MUI Library, Handlebars, HTML5, CSS3
- SQL, MySQL, PostgreSQL, GraphQL
- MongoDB, Compass, Mongoose, Apollo Sandbox, Insomnia, Sequelize, DBeaver, RDS
- NodeJS, Spring, Express, RESTful API, Axios
- MVC, RESTful API, Object Oriented Programming, Data Structures and Design Patterns
- Apollo Server, HTTP Servlets, Tomcat Server, Workbox, Webpack, JWT Authentication
- Git, GitHub, GitLab, Bash/Shell, Terminal

Soft Skills

- Ability to work effectively with people with differing levels of technical knowledge.
- Excellent communication and interpersonal skills.
- Ability to work independently and as part of a team.
- Excellent judgment and integrity with the ability to make timely and sound decisions.
- Attention to details, perfectionism and a pixel-perfect eye.
- Ability to clearly communicate with a team, balance job obligations with other commitments, self-initiate and take responsibility for tasks.

Languages

- English
- Georgian